VOJTECH VITEK

CONTACT

E-mail vojtech.vitek@gmail.com

Phone +1-647-773-0468

Location Toronto, ON, Canada

LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/vojtechvitek

GitHub github.com/VojtechVitek

StackOverflow stackoverflow.com/users/385548



SUMMARY

I'm friendly and positively thinking backend developer with strong Linux background. I enjoy working with Golang, Docker, Kubernetes, Bash, AngularJS and React.js. Besides my passion for IT, I like traveling and meeting new people. I do several sports actively and I'm musician. I've relocated from Prague (Czech Rep.) to Toronto in 2014 to challenge myself and start a new life experience. I'm interested in relocating to the U.S. in the near future. I'm open to new challenges and opportunities.

WORK EXPERIENCE

2 months Software Engineer at Pressly

Golang Backend Development Feb 2015 - Present

Responsible for designing and maintaining high available Golang REST API microservices with MongoDB, PostgreSQL and LedisDB storages. Responsible for Docker deployments on EC2. www.pressly.com

- Golang, REST, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, LedisDB, Travis CI
- Docker, Ubuntu, EC2

2.5 years Software Engineer at Red Hat

Golang Backend Development & PHP Expert Aug 2012 - Feb 2015

Developing OpenShift 3 (Golang), the next generation PaaS built on top of Google Kubernetes and Docker containers. Responsible for Developer Experience and PHP and Zend Server environments. www.openshift.com

- Golang, REST, Bash, PHP, Zend Server, MongoDB, Etcd, Jenkins
- Docker, Kubernetes, EC2, RHEL, Atomic, CentOS, Fedora

2.5 years Associate Software Engineer at Red Hat

GNU/Linux Software Maintenance

Oct 2010 - Jul 2012

Fedora/RHEL package maintainer. Responsible for dozen core GNU/Linux applications, most notably PHP 5.x + PECLs, Rsync, GNU Awk, tcsh, gzip, xinetd, less and sed. www.redhat.com

• RPM, Bash, C/C++, PHP 5.x, Awk

4.5 years SysAdmin & PHP Devel. at Blue Solutions

Linux Administration, Drupal Development

2009 - 2013 Side job. Co-founder of dot-com company focusing on robust web portals and e-shops. Responsible for VM-based CentOS server infrastructure. Developing custom Drupal 6/7 modules. www.modryweb.cz

• CentOS 6, DNS, Varnish, Nginx, PHP-FPM, OPcache, Redis, MySQL

• Drupal 7, Drupal Commerce, JavaScript, jQuery

EDUCATION

2007 - 2011 Brno University of Technology, Czech Rep.

Bachelor's Degree

Information Technology - Bachelor's Degree. Graduated with "Native Code Browser Extensions" Bachelor thesis, focused on front-end browser extensions, C/C++ NPAPI plugins for Mozilla Firefox, Google Chrome and Opera browsers and applications sandboxed using Native Client.

Outstanding Results

Placed in top 5% students and received several scholarships for outstanding academic results. www.fit.vutbr.cz

Exchange Studies

Erasmus exchange studies at Yildiz Technical University, Istanbul, Turkey, focused on Unix operating systems and Oracle database storage technologies. Gained "A" grades in all courses taken and received scholarship for outstanding academic results. www.yildiz.edu.tr/en/

Network Academy Research Responsible for developing software tools and drivers for custom High-speed 100G Network Cards, CentOS/Debian server infrastructure and RPM/DEB packaging. www.liberouter.org

CERTIFICATIONS

- Red Hat Certified System Administrator (RHCSA), 120-019-294
- Red Hat Project Management Academy, 2012

AWARDS & INTERNATIONAL SCHOLARSHIPS

- 2011, Winner of the CZ.NIC VIP 3 Open-Source Competition
- 2010, Winner of the CZ.NIC VIP 2 Open-Source Competition
- 2009, Winner of the Student EEICT Academy Project Competition
- 2009, Winner of the GE Foundation International Scholarship for the 15 most accomplished students of technical universities in the Central and Eastern Europe

May 8, 2015